# **MANUEL ORTIZ**

## VIDEO GAME DEVELOPER

I am a freelance video game programmer with 3 years of experience in the personal and professional field. I have implemented features in AR projects, and I also have experience in cinematic development in Unity. Additionally, I am an advanced student of the Systems Engineering career.

## **EXPERIENCE**

Freelance Cinematic artist

Studio Soup, Remote

JULY 2023 - PRESENT

- IMPROVING CINEMATIC SHOTS BY ADDING VARIOUS CAMERA ELEMENTS AND ENHANCING SCENES.
- ENHANCING PRODUCTION TIMES BY PROVIDING CAMERA CONTROL TOOLS.

Freelance game developer

3DAR, Remote

JANUARY 2022 - DECEMBER 2022

- IMPROVED THE SCORING SYSTEM OF AN AR GAME DEVELOPED ON SNAPCHAT.
- IMPLEMENTED A UI SYSTEM AS A BEHAVIOR ENHANCEMENT.
- UPDATED THE PARTICLE SYSTEM TO A MORE EFFICIENT ONE, IMPROVING PERFORMANCE.

#### • Resistencia, Argentina 🏻

- (+54)9-3794-350947
- ortizmanuel@pm.me
- www.linkedin.com/in/manuel-enrique-ortiz
- github.com/manuelxp95
- manuel-ortiz-portfolio.vercel.app/

# SKILLS

- Unity
- C#
- C++
- Unreal Engine 5 & Blueprints
- Godot
- Git & Github
- Blender
- Python
- Node.js
- Adobe Photoshop

# **SELF PROJECTS**

2023 - Revolución Tecnobotánica

https://elithne.itch.io/revolucion-tecnobotanica

Game created during the ADVA game jam, applying knowledge in UE5.

2023 - PSXRobbery (Short Film)

https://youtu.be/V\_bPS9pHbRU

I managed to create this short film with a PSI aesthetic, entirely made in Unreal Engine 5.

2023 - Path Between Dimensions

https://ortizmanuel.itch.io/path-between-dimensions

Project in 2.5D dimension shift carried out in Unity Engine for the GameDev.tv JAM. Made in 5 days

2022 - METEORITOS

github.com/manuelxp95/Repo\_cenit

Have you played Asteroids (1976) BUT IN GODOT.

2022 - ROAD TO CARPINCHO

github.com/manuelxp95/RoadToCarpincho

Adventure game in with you can play as a carpincho, inspired in similar games like Frogger but a little touch of action

### EDUCATION

Epic BootCamp ANIMATION |
2023

• UT-HUB

PRODUCTION AND UNREAL ENGINE COURSE | 2022

ADVA - ASOCIACIÓN DE
 DESARROLLADORES DE VIDEOJUEGOS
 ARGENTINA | 2022

INTRODUCTION TO UNREAL ENGINE | 2022

• POTRERO DIGITA

UNITY JUNIOR PROGRAMMER | 2022

• UNITY TECHNOLOGIES

**PIXELAB | 2022** 

· GOBIERNO, CHACO

INGENIERIA EN SISTEMAS DE INFORMACION | 2013 - Present

· UTN FRRE, RESISTENCIA



PORTFOLIO

manuel-ortiz-portfolio.vercel.app/